We've been expecting you
Downton Abbey is a drama, romance, history film directed by Michael Engler.
The beloved Crawleys and their intrepid staff prepare for
the most important moment of their lives.
A royal visit from the King and Queen of England will unleash scandal, romance and
intrigue that will leave the future of Downton hanging in the balance.
Robert Crawley, played by Hugh Bonneville.
Edith Crawley, played by Laura Carmichael.
Charles Carson, played by Jim Carter.
Phyllis Baxter, played by Raquel Cassidy.
John Bates, played by Brendan Coyle.
Mary Crawley, played by Michelle Dockery.
Downton Abbey is a 2019 historical drama film directed by Michael Engler from a screenplay by
Julian Fellowes, based on the television series of the same name created by Fellowes.
The film continues the storyline from the series, with
much of the original cast returning.
A sequel, Downton Abbey: A New Era, was released in the United Kingdom in April 2022 and a
second sequel, Downton Abbey: The Grand Finale, was released in September 2025.
Set in 1927, this film depicts a royal visit to the
Crawley family's stately home in Yorkshire.
As royal staff members descend on Downton, an assassin has
also arrived and attempts to kill the monarch.
After the series ended, a film adaptation was reportedly being considered
in April 2016, with Fellowes working on an outline plot.
The producers confirmed that a feature-length film would be made in July 2018, and principal photography started in London
later the following month, and in other places in England, including Shepperton Studios and Highclere Castle.
Filming ended that November, with a $13–20 million budget.
Downton Abbey premiered at the Odeon Luxe Leicester Square in London on 9 September 2019, and was released in
the United Kingdom on 13 September and in the United States on 20 September, by Focus Features.
The film received generally positive reviews from
critics and grossed $194.7 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of yorkshire, period drama,
upstairs downstairs, 1920s, based on tv series.
The tone is emotional.